Eduardo Guerrero

Langton Lodge, N16 8SU, London United Kingdom





I am a versatile product design consultant with more than 9 years of experience in the innovation sector, helping companies (from start-ups to multinational corporations) to launch strategically products, services and ideas to the market using design thinking tools and methodologies.

Work Experience

Senior Product Design Consultant - Full Time

Company: ROKi Digital 04/2021- Current (London)

Principal Product designer for a variety of projects of different sectors (Fintech, Ecommerce, SaaS,...):

- Definition of the UX process in the company.
- · Definition of the Figma files structure and the way to work internally and with the different stakeholders.
- · Research workshops (Persona, Empathy Maps, Business Canvas, SWOT, Priorisation...)
- Creation of Low/Mid fidelity prototypes to test in front of users to get their insights and iterate on the website interface and experience (includes A/B testing, remote testing, interviews post website use...).
- · Design and build client's Design Systems.
- · Definition of the UI and brand identity.

Senior Product Design Consultant - Contractor

Company: webegin.today 05/2020-02/2021 (London)

Principal Product designer for the start-up "webegin.today", a job platform that avoids any type of bias from the hiring company by the creation of an anonymous process when applying for a job:

- Design of the website flow, building wireframes and information architecture to define the website experience and the new hiring process.
- Definition of the UI and brand identity of the website and company.
- One to one user interviews (hiring managers and website users) to learn about the problems they find when hiring or job hunting, and converting them to insights to solve in the new platform.
- Creation of Low/Mid fidelity prototypes to test in front of users to get their insights and iterate on the website interface and experience (includes A/B testing, remote testing, interviews post website use...).

Senior Product Design Consultant - Contractor

Company: Doble 11/2019 - 04/2020 (London)

Working to improve the UX of the products and giving support to the team with design related topics:

- · Low/Mid Prototyping of manuals (digital and print) using Agile methodology
- · Creation of the new UI for the manuals and on-line content
- · Definition of the new products catalogue style

Mid-Weight Product Design Consultant

Company: Studio Make Believe 06/2016 - 06/2019 (London)

Working in the UX, design, visual execution and engineering of ideas from different sectors (Transport, Medical, POS, Marketing,..):

- User and Environment Research to get insights and inputs to detect problems or new opportunities for the brief. This includes final user interviews, stakeholders interviews, client's data analysis, customer journey...
- · Ideation of new concepts answering client's brief (Hand sketching, Solidworks, Rhino,...)
- Generation of visuals to show ideas, finishes and materials (Sketching and Rendering)
- Engineering of new products from a prototype (3D printing, CNC, Laser cutting, Metal bending...) to mass production
- · Supplier engagement and management
- · Client presentation, including presentation flow and structure

Jr Product Design Consultant - Freelance

Company: Freelance 06/2015 - 06/2016 (Barcelona)

Implementation of projects related to design for SME's of different sectors:

- Client and stakeholders management
- Cash-flow, budget control, invoicing...
- Full project delivery, from concept to manufacture

Jr Product Design Consultant

Company: Loop New Business Models 03/2013 - 06/2015 (Barcelona)

Project management in the field of product design, from product conceptualization, external team coordination, structuring of content, presentation and client facing:

- · Control of Cash Flow, suppliers orders...
- Multitask simultaneous projects at different stages and different scopes:FMCG, Home Appliances, Industrial equipment, Health, Packaging, Merchandise...
- · Design thinking application; Brainstorm and sketchstorm organisation, storyboard application, map of actors ...)

Education

Front-end Engineer

Codecademy Certificate 02/2021 - Present (London)

Data Analysis for Management

London School of Economics Certificate 12/2018 - 03/2019 (London)

Industrial Design Engineering

ELISAVA Degree 09/2009 - 07/2013 (Barcelona)

Graphic Design Technician

Cipsa Diploma 06/2012 - 12/2012 (Barcelona)

Technical Architecture

UPC Degree 09/2006 - 06/2009 (Barcelona)

Awards

Red Dot Design Award 2016

Part of the design team in the CWP V3 / Evolution Air Traffic controller working position for Indra.

Skills

- · Advanced Figma (including Atomic Design and Design Systems)
- · Advanced Sketch
- · Advance Adobe Pack (Adobe XD, Illustrator, Photoshop, Adobe Indesign)
- · Intermediate CSS/HTML
- · Basic Javascript
- Tableau (Data analysis)
- Advance Microsof Office (Word, Powerpoint, Excel)
- Design thinking tools and methodologies (Brainstorming, UCD, Personas, Service Blueprints, Stakeholders maps, User interviews...)

Language

- · English (Fluent)
- · Spanish (Native)
- Catalan (Native)